#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/dhruvishah5 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Java

С

C++

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Hindi (Native or Bilingual) Gujarati (Native or Bilingual)

### Honors-Awards

Competent Communicator
Competent Leader

# Dhruvi Shah

Software Engineer at Google Bengaluru

## Summary

I am currently working as a Software Engineer at Google. I work towards understanding User Generated Content (UGC) on Maps, moderating it, and keeping abusive content away from Google Maps.

Prior to this I worked as a Manager in the Institutional Securities Tech (IST) division at Morgan Stanley where I worked as a backend developer in the Fixed Income division developing applications that facilitate Deal Syndication.

I have worked on languages and technologies ranging from Java 8, C++, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, MapReduce pipelines, along with various Database technologies.

Apart from being an enthusiastic technical developer, I am also a passionate Toastmaster and have achieved Competent Communicator and Competent Leader awards so far in the Toastmasters' journey. I am actively involved in various Technical Club and Financial Club activities at Morgan Stanley and am part of the team running the Agile initiative within the firm.

An engineer by profession, a toastmaster by passion, and a learning enthusiast, I am always keen on accepting new challenges and solving innovative problems. I am equally fond of travelling, reading, and engaging in healthy discussions.

# Experience

Google Software Engineer November 2019 - Present (10 months) Bengaluru Area, India

Morgan Stanley

3 years 11 months

Manager

January 2019 - November 2019 (11 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Worked as a backend developer in the Fixed Income division developing applications that facilitate Deal Syndication. I have been working on the project since it's inception, which has helped me sharpen my application design and implementation skills along with expanding my horizon in the financial business domain.

Senior Technical Associate

January 2018 - January 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Bengaluru Area, India

**Technical Associate** 

January 2017 - January 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Bengaluru Area, India

Started working as a backend developer in the Securitized Products Group team of Fixed Income department.

Worked on Syndicate Tool application that facilitates Deal Syndication using Scrum framework for Agile development methodology.

Felicitated with Rookie Award for being the best new comer in the Institutional Securities Tech division at Morgan Stanley.

**Techical Analyst** 

August 2016 - January 2017 (6 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Went through a rigorous four months of Technology Analyst Program comprising of Technical as well as Financial training.

Technical Analyst Intern

January 2016 - July 2016 (7 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Interned with Banking and Payment Services department of Wealth Management division at Morgan Stanley.

During my internship, I worked on designing a rule engine that can auto accept/reject huge volumes of incoming transactions by validating it against a set of predefined rules.

Google Software Development Intern May 2015 - July 2015 (3 months)

As a part of Google Summer Tech Internship, I worked with Google Apps for Work team for adding works-with feature in Google Apps Marketplace. The project included writing a pipeline that uses MapReduce for tagging the apps based on Google app integration it is built upon.

### Education

Dhirubhai Ambani Institute of Information and Communication Technology

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Information and Communication Technology · (2012 - 2016)